NICHOLAS MASETE

Ntinda, Commercial Road · +256775406406/ +256755688019

nicholasmasete72@gmail.com,https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-masete-98b157101/ • <u>Twitter:@NicholasMasete</u>,Blog:medium.com/@nicholasmasete,GITHUB: https://github.com/masete

IT SPECIALIST

Highly organized and diligent professional drawing upon three(3) years of progressive experience in ICT, customer experience and Data management for smooth and productive ICT/Data quality. I like accomplishing assigned tasks with open mind within the stipulated time period. I pay close attention to even the smallest detail. I can adapt and adopt adequately fast to any challenging work environment, currently exploring software quality assurance in depth.

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2021 - PRESENT

DATA ENGINEER, DIGEST AFRICA

Develop data dashboards using plotly dash, Research about AI and its relevance in startups at real time, clean analyse and exract insights from data, mine social media data when needed and interact with final consumer's to pick their mind on what their needs are.

DEC 2019 - JAN 2021

DATA SCIENTIST, DINAMIC PROJECT MANAGERS LTD

Developed a data dashboard in python flask framework + canvajs, participated in writing reports and documentation of the software. Server monitoring, Software and hardware troubleshooting. Provide technical support to the procurement team for tech devices purchased. Attended startegic meetings with our stakeholders Makerere University, NDA and URA staff as main technical lead from my organisation.

Review and analyze system specifications.

I also worked as the QA tester and effectively effected the following develop effective strategies and test plans ,Execute test cases (manual or automated) and analyze results ,Evaluate product code according to specifications ,Create logs to document testing phases and defects ,Report bugs and errors to development teams ,Help troubleshoot issues ,Conduct post-release/ post-implementation testing ,Work with cross-functional teams to ensure quality throughout the software development life cycle.

JULY 2019 - DEC 2019

DATA ENGINEER FELLOW, POLLICY.ORG

Trained partner organisations on data collection tools like kobotoolbox, odk and canva for data presenattion. Interviewed most NGO's and private companies during my qualitative data collection exercise. Hosted and mantained a machine learning question and answer system. Mined social media data to analyse the performance of our campaigns. Developed conversational ui's to collect data about ogbv and cgbv. Troubleshooting printers and software and hardwares.

JAN 2019 - JULY 2019

IT SUPPORT GRADUATE TRAINEE, UNITED NATIONS POPULATION FUND (UNFP)

Setup work station for new staff to the country office. Continuous network and internet connectivity. Install and configure all IT equipment. Provide ict support to the field staff. Document and provide ict report on daily basis. Update and communicate ict policies in a timely manner. Ensure timely resolution of ict queries including biometric equipment. keep the records of the inventories. Support all online meetings in the baordroom using video conferencing tools and google hangouts. Religously backing up data and performing regular and planned updates of the organisations software's. Closley monitoring the server room and resolving any issues arising up.

JUNE 2018 - JAN 2019 JUNIOR DEVELOPER.

Developed an in house content management system in PHP using the laravel framework. Setup work station for new staff to the country office. Continuous network and internet connectivity. Install and configure all IT equipment. Provide ict support to the field staff. Document and provide ict report on daily basis. Ensure timely resolution of ict queries including biometric equipment. keep the records of the inventories.

EDUCATION

GRADUATED JANUARY 2019

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, MAKERERE UNIVERSITY

Software engineering is a 4 years course intended to prepare her students to innovate on real world problems and provide functional solutions. In my final year i worked on a threat intelligence platform to protect networks from internal and external network attacks in addition to the projects developed in my recess term. Problem solving, design structure and IT security.

2012 - 2013 UACE

PHYSICS, MATHEMATICS, ICT AND ECON, MANDELA SS, HOIMA

I was among the best 10 students in my class scoring 15/20. A member of the debate club and also a cordinator in scripture union.

2008 - 2011 UCE

UCE, KINYARA SS, MASINDI

I served as a seceretary general both at school and district level, a vibrant member of the interact club, and a President of the Computer club. Represented my school as part of the members on the school football team on district level in the cocacola school football challenge.

SKILLS

- Software development using Django and flask microframeworks during my andela bootcamp periods.
- Data analysis in pandas + numpy and dashboard developmet using plotly dash.
- Git, TDD, OOP, Selenium

- Server room mantaince, troubleshooting and monitoring.
- Software and hardware troubleshooting including servers and biometric devices
- MYSQL, POSTGRES, MONGO
- Networks, System administration

ACTIVITIES

- **1.** Completed a 9 Month course on Leadership with the global leadership summit, practical skills in people management, expectation management, how to get the most of people around us and team work and many more skills where passed on to me in this period.
- **2.** Completed a digital marketing master class with the innovation village in Kampala Uganda. Marketing using tools like laptops, phones, face book, whatsapp and other social media platforms
- **3.** Completed a data science master class with the innovation village in Kampala Uganda. Skills in data collection, analysis and visualization and giving solutions to real world problems with our learnt skills at the period.
- **4.** I was part of the Andela development challenge level up's and for 6 months I dived deep in API development with flask and Django, the use of Git and Github and more developers tools like travis, codeclimate, code quality, Test driven development.
- 5. BSAFE United Nations Security Course training

1 WANDA DAVID Senior account

executive
Minet Limited

Tel: +256774242427

Email:

david.wanda@minet.co.ug

2 WELIKHE GEOFREY

Area programs manager-WORLD VISION
ASAMUK area programs
Amuria District
Tel:+256779962995/
+256701303958

Email:

geofrey_werikhe@wvi.org

3 IVAN OPIO Senior IT Officer UNFPA, Country Office

Tel: +256777087545 **Email:** opio@unfpa.org